Well, Dad needs to get going.
I want you to try and
stay out of trouble for me.
Listen to your big sister.
I wanna go with you!
Yeah bring us with you!
I'm so sorry, but no. I can't.
Hey! Stop acting so selfish
and behave yourselves.
You're making this harder for him.
Fine. Try and
help them to get along.
I will! Good luck
with your work!
Thanks. All right. Goodbye.
See you soon!
Darling...
I'm sorry.
Take care of the kids.
Let's go.
Right. So, if they attack,
they'll do it during my speech, yes?
Nothing's guaranteed, sir,
but that seems like
the strongest possibility.
Most of Marley's highest ranked officers
will be gathered for it.
That's a rare occurrence.
I should mention,
in accordance with protocol,
we're waiting to determine
escape routes till later,
lest the information should leak.
I'll note that many VIPs
will be arriving by carriage.
Got it. Seat the officers
in a special section.
Group them, preferably at
the edge of the crowd.
Is this really what you want to do, sir?
We Tyburs haven't just
sat around enjoying ourselves.
At least this generation hasn't.
We've been at work.
Fostering relationships
with the world's ruling class.
Improving people's
perceptions of Eldians,
and keeping track of
events on Paradis Island.
That said, we neglected
to watch our backs.
Before we knew it, our enemies
had crossed the sea,
when they were at our necks.
I fear that we could
find our throats slashed
at any moment now.
It's become clear that
the infiltrators received help
from within Marley,
and the unsettling truth is
that we still don't know who gave it.
As you surely know,
our motherland, Marley,
has many enemies.
Even within our own military.
And if you want to
smoke out your enemies,
you light a fire beneath them.
We know when and where
the foe intends to attack us.
That ought to give us the advantage.
Unless you have a better one,
this is the plan.
Even if we can predict their moves,
we're putting far too much at stake.
We're sacrificing incompetent officers.
If the enemy's goal is to damage
our military, then so be it.
This is an opportunity.
Start picking replacements now.
The party will approve anyone you choose
for your reformed military.
But, sir, so many will die.
And most will be Eldian civilians.
They're spawn of the devil, aren't they?
Don't change on me now, Commander.
You've ordered countless
Eldians up and over
to meet their deaths in a hellscape
of barbed wire, landmines, and bullets.
So these ones won't be wearing uniforms.
That changes nothing.
You just need to keep doing
what you've always done.
Allow me to say one thing.
This isn't a war.
We don't know our enemies, their goals,
or how they plan to attack us.
When they make their move,
the crowd surrounding you
will erupt in chaos.
Lord Tybur.
If we go forward with this,
and use you to bait the enemy,
I doubt I'll be able to protect you.
They'll do whatever it takes
to make sure that you die.
Of course.
I'm prepared for that.
Unless I stand on that stage,
the world will not take notice.
There must be officers, ambassadors,
and journalists from around
the globe in that audience.
And crucially,
the Eldian civilians who are killed,
myself included, must be mourned by all.
As victims of an
"unforeseen attack."
If I escaped while
my people died en masse,
the world would not rally to our cause.
I fully believe the Eldian race
was spawned by the devil.
But I'm just as sure that
we're devils ourselves.
Gabi! Udo! Get up!
On your feet! Hurry!
Huh...? Zofia...?
- -Zofia, no! Zofia!
- -Udo, you can't!
- -Zofia!
- -Listen to me!
Come and help me!
We have to lift this...
Udo!
You've fulfilled your
duty as a Tybur, brother.
I'm so proud of you.
Commander Magath!
The War Hammer Titan
is getting pulverized!
Commander! The Warrior
Unit's gone silent!
General Calvi and the rest
of the brass are dead, sir!
Should we start evacuating...
We have to fall back before we're killed!
We need orders!
Commander!
Commander?
It was a harmless plink,
but the first shot has now been fired.
Our counterattack's begun.
I never thought they'd
make such a grand entrance.
What's more, that looks to be the usurper
of the Founding Titan down there.
The Attack Titan.
We're up against Eren Jaeger himself.
Just means he's saved us
a trip to the island.
Get in position, men!
Prepare for battle!
Understood, sir!
Sheesh, what's all this commotion about?
Don't just stand there!
We have to run...
Now, I don't want any of you forgetting.
The first attack that pierced
the enemy came from my gun.
Shit! What is this?
The whole town's like a battlefield!
Is he okay?
No. We need to
get him to the hospital.
Oh no. Udo.
What the hell?
Falco! Where are you?
Okay. What's going on here?
Based on all the tremors,
I think Titans must be
fighting on the surface.
Wait, are you serious?
You have to admit that it would explain
why that soldier trapped us down here.
We need to join the fight quickly.
But how?
What the hell?
You're late!
- -Sorry, Pieck!
- -Are you two okay?
Yeah! Throw us a rope!
On it!
The Panzer Unit. How'd they
know we'd be here?
I thought Beardy looked suspicious,
so I told them to follow us.
Back then?
There's something up with this soldier.
Shadow us for a while.
A Titan attacked and killed Lord Tybur
during his speech!
For real?
The War Hammer Titan's
keeping it occupied
for the time being.
How far to the Cart's armor?
It's back at HQ!
We can equip it in 15 minutes.
Do it in ten.
Roger that.
I'm going on ahead.
Hold on, Porco.
Don't rush in till you know what you're...
What the...?
There's no way.
How'd they get here?
We hit it!
Yeah, take that!
These Anti-Titan cannons pack a punch!
This is our chance.
We can finish off Eren Jaeger
here and now.
If we strip them of the Founding
Titan, they're finished!
- -Not so.
- -Huh?
If we kill the Founder,
it will only postpone the problem.
What we need is to have
the War Hammer Titan eat it!
Our mission is to make sure that happens.
Right. But, sir. It's just...
It doesn't actually
look like the War Hammer's
trying to eat it.
Look at that!
The War Hammer's a monster!
It beat the Attack Titan!
The War Hammer wins!
That's him. Eren Jaeger.
It... It's gonna finish him off!
Usurper Eren Jaeger.
Before you die, you may
utter your final words.
It's time, Mikasa.
Glad to see that all of you made it.
Please. Eren. Come home.
Our chain of command has been shattered.
This is the ultimate test
of our military's strength.
Cancel the special
vigilance training at once.
Bring that entire division
down from the mountains.
Call in the fleet as well.
And bring in all 30,000 soldiers
we have stationed to the east and west.
I want the Internment Zone
sealed off! Surround us.
Don't let a single Island Devil escape,
especially not the Founder!
Go ahead and wreak havoc while you can.
Your fates are sealed.
This has gone exactly as Willy planned.
The entire world now considers
the Eldian Empire a threat.
And every nation that
lost government officials
to this massacre is
now a party to this war.
This world can no longer
risk letting you live.
But, you must've realized
that going into this.
Which means...
Damn devils!
Fight! Shoot!
Idiots.
Hey! Are you trying to burn down
the whole Internment Zone?
We need to try to keep civilian
casualties to a minimum.
Understand me, Floch?
Everyone here is an enemy.
These are just our enemy's homes.
Don't forget what they did to us.
The Titans who've been
slaughtering our people
for years came from here, right?
They've been eating us alive!
So they've got this coming and then some!
Seriously, you have to
stop thinking like that.
Look there.
He's telling us something.
That we have to fight.
We can't just cower behind our walls,
waiting for death to come.
We need to fight like he does.
Like devils.
Hey. Eren.
You understand what
you've done, don't you?
You've killed so many civilians.
Innocent people. Kids.
There's no taking this back.
It's not over, Mikasa.
That's impossible!
I blew up the nape of its neck.
And I crushed its nape
with all my strength.
Yet, it's still alive.
Huh.
I think I get it now.
The War Hammer Titan uses hardening
to make whatever it needs.
And it won't die,
no matter how much damage
we deal to its neck.
Mikasa. Keep it
occupied for me.
If this works, I'll be
able to eat the War Hammer.
I'm truly sorry,
but we're overwhelmed as it is.
And that child is already deceased.
No. Wait. You haven't
even looked at him yet!
If you're actually a Warrior candidate,
then wake up and look at reality.
Doctor! We need you!
Right! On my way!
Gabi. You should
go find your family.
I'm not sure if anywhere's safe, but
get as far from the plaza as you can.
I just need to track down Falco...
I'm going, too.
Because I don't get why
Udo and Zofia... needed to die.
Wait. It's not safe, Gabi!
Hey, stop!
You're heading straight
into a war zone, kid!
Gabi!
What are you doing here?
Oh, it's you two. I'm ready
to fight, so let me pass!
Stop acting like a stupid brat.
Find your family and lay low.
What the...?
We're under attack!
Where from?
Above us!
Oh shit. Start
running and don't...
Son of a...
Oh my god.
This street's blocked off.
Let's go, Sasha.
Slow down.
You forgot that we need to
set a lamp out, Conny.
Oh. Right.
We've stalled their reinforcements.
What about the lights?
All of them are in place now.
Are things going all right?
They are for now at least.
If we can take that
thing out soon, we'll be fine.
But that's a big if.
Looks like anything could
happen at this point.
The only way to find out
what will come next
is to make it out of
this mess alive. So focus.
I knew that something was off.
There was something abnormal about
the way the War Hammer materialized.
It was the first time I'd seen a Titan
form from the feet up.
Not from its neck,
but from beneath the stage
it was standing on.
So that's where its body is.
Damn it. The War Hammer's
about to get eaten!
This is the moment I've been waiting for!
I'm taking the Founder right now!
Eren!
Why... can't I bite?
Wait. Could that be him?
Is that Ackermann?
I need to fall back.
What the hell?
Can't you see I'm a Titan?
Are a bunch of humans
really about to come and kill me?
No. They're not humans.
They're devils!
The devils of Paradis.
Marley's Warriors have met their match
in these soldiers who
soar through the air.
Gabi and Falco cry out to Reiner.
Will he hear their pleas?
Next episode: "Assault."